はい
雪音　そっち終わったら店の方な
Yukine, tend to the shop
when you're done over there.
よし
Okay!
おでんあがりました
ああ　朝早くからご苦労さん
おはようございます
日和　いらっしゃい
All right.
本当にここでバイト始めたんだね
The oden is ready!
Already working hard this
early in the morning, I see.
まぁな
せめて取ったりした分ぐらいは返してぇし
Good morning!
Hiyori! Welcome!
雪音君
そんなふうに言われちゃ大黒おじさんも断れんよ
So you really have started
working here part-time.
W-Well, you know...
いろいろあったが
I at least wanna pay back the money I took.
まともにやってく気になったんだな
Yukine-kun...
それもあるけど
Not even mean old Daikoku
could say no after hearing that.
夜トの稼ぎがねぇから　パートだパート
A lot's happened, but it looks like you've finally been set straight.
そうそう　日和ちゃんにも頼みごとあんだろう
I guess so...
そりゃあもういいって
なに
but it's also because, between me and Yato, someone has to be making money!
いや
日和ちゃん　もうすぐ高校生だろう
Oh, right. Don't you have something you wanted to ask Hiyori-chan, too?
だから　中学の教科書や問題集がほしいんだってさ
I-I said it doesn't matter anymore!
みんなと同じことがしてぇんだと
What is it?
Well, uh...
You're going to be a
high schooler soon, right?
どうせ捨てんだろう
He was hoping he could have your old textbooks and workbooks.
えぇ
いいよ　全部あげる
He wants to do the same
stuff everyone else does.
何なんだおめぇら
I mean, if you were gonna
throw them away anyway...
はい　いたいた
お二人さん
Huh?!
Of course! You can have all of them!
こっちの支払いも忘れないでね
私たちひよりんに頼まれて夜トちゃん助けたじゃない
What's gotten into you guys?!
Oh, there you are, you two!
うち一回こんだけかかんのよ
Don't forget about the
money you owe me, okay?
五円ですね
Huh?
You asked us to save Yato-chan,
remember, Hiyorin?
五百万
んで　二回だから
We charge this much per request!
一千…万
Oh, 5 yen?
大丈夫
5 million.
And since we helped twice...
ひよりん可愛いし素人だから
すぐお金できると思う
50,000
500,000
5,000,000
7,000,000
8,000,000
9,000,000
10,000,000
待て小福
10... million...
日和の場合は学割が効くはずだろう
Don't worry!
あ　そっか
You're pretty cute and inexperienced, so I'm sure you can earn it in no time!
じゃ　百万でいいよ
よかったな　九割引きだぞ
このやり繰り上手
Wait, Kofuku.
貧乏神相手に 一本は安い安い
Hiyori should get a student discount.
Oh, right!
Just 1 million, then!
私の体質も変わってないくせに
Sweet! 90 percent off!
That's what I call a steal!
借金だって
You're bargaining with the god of poverty like it's a walk in the park!
夜トも払いなさい
日和ちゃんはどこの団体の子
You still haven't fixed my body,
and now you're gonna
throw that debt on me?!
You will help me pay!
What wrestling federation
does she belong to?
弾丸込めた小銃を　僕は片手に持っている
Noragami
震えた君のいる場所へ　足を早め向かっている
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
焦る心を急かしただけ
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
留まる気配もなく　進んでいく
チクタク　針はチクタクと
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
チクタク　針はチクタクと
終わりと始まりの境目
aseru kokoro wo sekashita dake
Making my heart race even faster
終わりと始まりの境目
チクタク　針はチクタクと
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
チクタク　針はチクタクと
全て重なった
todomaru kehai mo naku susunde yuku
Going on and on endlessly
全て重なった
閉口して　僕は待っていた
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
owari to hajimari no sakaime
In the small gap between end and beginning
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
owari to hajimari no sakaime
閉口して　僕は待っていた
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
閉口して　僕は待っていた
subete kasanatta
That's where everything will happen
ドアを蹴破る　その音を
閉口して　僕は待っていた
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was waiting helplessly
閉口して　僕は待っていた
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was waiting helplessly
閉口して　僕は待っていた
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
usugurai heya hitorikiri
In this dark room all by myself
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
閉口して　僕は待っていた
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
閉口して　僕は待っていた
もう怖れることはないよ
doa wo keyaburu sono oto wo
For the sound of the door being kicked in
もう怖れることはないよ
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
usugurai heya hitorikiri
In this dark room all by myself
固く閉ざされたドアを蹴破った
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
吸い付いた銃口が跳ねて
mou osoreru koto wa nai yo
There's nothing to fear now
昨日の僕を貫いた
mou osoreru koto wa nai yo
おやすみ　その絶望を受け取って
dangan kometa shoujuu wo motte
With a loaded rifle in hand
おやすみ　その絶望を受け取って
dan
gan
ko
me
ta
sho
u
ju
wo
mo
明日への僕は歩き始めた
tte
kataku tozasareta doa wo keyabutta
I kick down the locked door
明日への僕は歩き始めた
ka
ta
ku
to
za
sa
re
ta
do
a
wo
ke
ya
bu
tta
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
suitsuita juukou ga hanete
The gun recoils
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
su
i
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
tsu
i
ta
ju
u
ko
ga
ha
ne
kinou no boku wo tsuranuita
As I pierce through my past self
ki
no
u
bo
ku
wo
tsu
ra
nu
i
ta
I accept the lingering despair
oyasumi sono zetsubou wo uketotte
ashita e no boku wa arukihajimeta
And start walking toward the future
mata kon'ya machiawaseyou
ma
ta
ko
n'
ya
ma
chi
a
wa
se
you
Let's meet again tonight
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:小然&千夜  翻译:maki&迩祢  校对:木落&叶隐  时间轴:Gissa  压制:久嘉
天神
Tenjin!
この前のお礼参りに来たぞ
I'm here to say thanks for the other day!
大変だったみたいだね　夜ト君
It sounds like you had a tough time, Yato-kun.
Oh? You think so?
あ　そう
Of course!
そうですよ
なんであそこまで安無を拗らせたんだか
Why would you ever let your blight get that bad?
I'm sure you were in pain long before that.
夜トさんは辛かったでしょうに
Sekki has rare, outstanding strength.
雪器は久々の逸材だ
I couldn't give him up just like that.
そう簡単に手放したくない
More than anything, I wanted
to properly reforge him.
とにかくこいつをちゃんと鍛えたかった
一発どぎつい灸をすえてやりたくて
I purposely let my condition worsen to give him a wake-up call.
わざと拗らせてみた
Well, I understand the sentiment, I suppose.
ま　分からなくもないけど
Anyway...
それにしても
マジ助かっちゃったよ
You seriously saved the day!
さすが伴音
I'd expect no less from
my former buddy Tomone!
俺の元相棒
真喩はね　肝の座わったいい子だよ
Mayu is a nice yet gutsy girl,
as a matter of fact.
どこぞの底辺で鍛えられたから
All thanks to a certain
lowlife who took her in.
ま　うちは厳しいし
Well, I am pretty strict.
おや　じゃ３Ｋじゃなくて４Ｋだね
Oh? So you follow the four Cs rather than the normal three.
臭い　汚い　稼ぎがないうえに厳しいか
Crass. Childish. Crude. Clueless.
This is...
お礼…
...how he thanks him?
参り
はいはい　向こうで話しようか
Come. Let us talk over here.
クール　かっこいい　輝いてる　綺麗好きの４Ｋだ
No! Cool, classy, confident, and cultured!
Huh? One of the Regalia is gone.
あれ　神器がお一人いませんね
Miyu-san, is it?
確か　実喩さん
Oh.
彼女ね
Yes, she was kicked out
for stinging Michizane-sama.
道真様を刺しちゃったから　破門されたの
魔が刺したの
She was corrupted?
What happened to you is
actually very contagious, you see.
雪音君がなったあれはとても感染力が強くてね
Just seeing or hearing about it is enough to infect others.
見聞きしただけでも感化されしまうの
When I grow up
please let me
become
a school
teacher.
Stinging a master even once
means immediate banishment.
一度でも主を刺したら即破門
Michizane-sama has always been strict about this rule.
ここはずっとこの仕来りで道真様をお守りしているわ
すみません　すみません
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Harming others or yourself...
他人を傷つけるのも
すみません
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
自分を傷つけるのも
すみません
名づけ親たる主を裏切る罪
is no different from betraying your master who named you.
Revoking your name and sending you away after
an ablution is actually considered a generous act.
禊をしてから名を取り
放ってくださるだけありがたいことよ
Because, if you're lucky,
a new master will take you in.
うまく行けば　また誰かに拾ってもらえる
でないと
But, without that mercy...
I'm sorry. It was all my fault.
すみません　俺のせいで
仕方がないわ
What's done is done.
ただ　そのことを気にしても　気には病まないでね
You mustn't let this bother you.
It would affect Yato-san.
夜トさんに触るわ
雪音君がああなった気持ち
We completely understand
how you were feeling.
私たちもよく分かる
Regalia are quickly corrupted if they don't maintain their Borderlines.
神器は一線を保っていないと
すぐに落ちてしまい
結局 あやかしと同じ死角に住まう彼岸のものだから
Because, ultimately, we're Far Shore beings
who dwell alongside Phantoms, out of sight.
気をつけて
Be careful.
常に闇はそばにあるわよ
The darkness is always
right there next to you.
Darkness...
闇
Even so, Yato-san refused to abandon you.
夜トさんはそれでも雪音君を見捨てなかったわ
これからは その名にかけて 主を守りなさい
You need to swear on your name that
you'll protect your master from now on.
Got it!
はい
I swear on my name "Yuki"!
雪の名にかけて
What?
何
ううん
Nothing.
By the way, Tenjin...
ときに天神
I was hoping you could
give me some advice.
ちょっと知恵を借りたいんだけど
Hm?
日和のことなんだけどさ
It's about Hiyori.
あいつ　事故ってから
Ever since her accident, she ends up in
her spirit form from time to time, you see.
生き霊になる体質になっちゃってさ
Ah.
それを治す依頼受けてんだけど
And I accepted her request to fix that.
これがもう　さっぱり分かんなくて
But I have absolutely
no idea what to do,
ずっとほうっておいてんだよね
so I've been putting it off all this time!
But she's helped me out a few times now,
でもあいつには何遍も助けてもらってるし
日和のために そろそろ本気で働こうと思うんだ
so I feel it's time to finally
get started on her job!
How pathetic can you be?
どんだけだめな子なんだね君は
じゃ君との縁を切ってみれば
Try cutting her ties with you, then.
Huh?
Doing so might just fix
her strange condition.
そうすれば　その妙な体質も治るかもしれないよ
Cut her ties?
縁を切るって
あの子は君を介してこちらの世界に焦点を合わせすぎている
Being connected to you is
pulling her closer to our world.
試しに切ってみなさいよ
Try cutting that connection
and see if it has any effect.
得意でしょう
That is your specialty.
Chapter 10
Regarded
with Hate
自宅より断然図書館のほうが捗るね
Studying at the library's way better than studying at home.
I know, right?
だね
よし　今日もよく頑張った
All right!
Another good day of studying!
来年はうちらも一応受験だしね
We have some important
exams after the new year.
一丁初詣は決めないと
We need to pick a shrine to pray at!
最後は神頼みだな
Yeah, can't forget to wish to a god!
無事に進学と健康とモテ期と交通安全とモテ期と家内安全と
I want to graduate, be healthy, be popular, travel safely,
be popular, and for my
family to be in good health!
モテ期二回言ったぞ
You wished to be popular twice.
It's that important.
大事だからな
You shouldn't keep the gods busy with too many wishes, you know.
そんなにたくさん頼んだら 神様困るよ
人の願いを聞いてこその神だろうが
Listening to people's wishes is their job!
神のほうの都合なんて知らんわ
Who cares about their schedules?
Oh, yeah.
そうだ　願い事っていえば
Speaking of wishes, there's this one god people have been talking about lately.
最近噂になってる神様いるよね
Oh, yeah. Him.
お　あれか
何
What's this about?
They say that if you tell him the
name of someone you want gone,
いなくなってほしい人の名前を教えると
本当に消してくれるらしいよ
he really will make them disappear for you.
蠃蚌様蠃蚌様　どうかお願いしますって奴だろう
"Rabou-sama, Rabou-sama! I beg of you!"
That's how it goes, right?
Yeah, that's it!
それそれ
Rabou-sama?
蠃蚌様
I've never heard of that god.
聞いたことのない神様だね
It's probably just an urban legend.
まぁ　流行でしょ
そうそうそう
Yeah.
Huh? Are those textbooks, Hiyori?
日和　それ教科書
しかも昔のじゃん
Wait, those are our old ones.
っんなもんどうすんだ
What are you doing with them?
I'm giving them to a friend!
友達にあげるの
Rest Stop
You kids working hard in here?
がきども　しっかりやってっか
大黒　俺茶漬けで
Daikoku! I'll have a tea snack!
てめぇ　何でうちにいる
What are you doing here?!
Oh, come on. Lighten up a little.
いいじゃねーか　つれねーな
ここは雪音に貸したんだ
I'm letting Yukine use this room! It ain't for you to relax in!
勝手にくっつくんな
お前は茶殻でも吸ってろ
And you can go suck on some tea leaves!
Man...
ったく
No good. Do it again.
だめです　やり直し
You're a pretty strict teacher, Hiyori.
日和　厳しいな
It's easy to mess up
these parts. Be careful.
こことここ　イージーミスだよ
気をつけてね
Okay.
はい
Let me see!
どれ　見してみ
The trick to learning this
stuff is visualizing it!
こういうのは書いて覚えるんだよ
There!
ほれ
枕草子の清少納言
The Pillow Book's Sei Shounagon,
方丈記の鴨長明
Houjouki's Kamo-no-Choumei,
and Tsurezuregusa's Yoshida Kenkou!
徒然草の吉田兼好
激うまっ
Those are great!
Amazed, are we?
恐れ入ったかね
ったく　俺が何年神様やってると思って
Do you know how long I've been a god—
Quit doodling on my stuff!
っちゅうか　落書きすんな
Don't refer to my talent as "doodling"!
俺の才能　落書きって言うな
だったらその才能仕事に繋げろ
Then earn some money with that talent!
ったく　邪魔ばっかしやがって
Man, you always gotta butt in!
Wh-What did you say?!
なんだと
なに
What?
N-Nothing.
な　何でもねー
Hiyori!
日和
Could you put the black beans in these?
Despite being in plain sight...
Still No Clues About Serial Street Slasher
Shimoito City Center District
Yesterday
Scene of the Incident
The street slasher has yet to be found...
昨夜にて　繁華街に起きた連続通り魔殺人事件の犯人は
黒豆ちゃん　つねてちょうだい
Okay!
はーい
There have been a lot of stories like that on the news lately.
未だに否確定おらず　人通りが
最近多いわね　この手のニュース
Be careful when you go on your New Year's shrine visit tonight.
夜の初詣　気をつけなさいね
大丈夫だよ
I'll be fine.
Serial Street Slashings
Investigation Task Force
to be Assembled Today
Yama-chan and Ami-chan will be with me.
やまちゃんあみちゃんも一緒だし
だといいけど
I'm still a bit worried.
You're not already asleep are you??
Let's go all out with this shrine visit!!
Yama
I can't believe you took a dumb job like this on New Year's Eve!
大晦日までこんなしょうもない仕事を受けやがって
年末大掃除はコツさえ掴めば
If you know all the tricks, year-end
cleaning can be some really lucrative work.
回転率のいい仕事なの
Still...
しかし
犬の癖に何この豪邸
Why does this dog have its own mansion?
Man, it's huge!
でっかいよな
ねぇ
It really is, huh?
いやだ　うそ
Whoa, no way! A heated floor?!
まさかの床暖房
Seriously?!
マジで
I'm so jealous!
羨ましい
はいはい
Hello! Delivery God Yato,
at your service 365 days a year!
こちら土日祝日年中無休 デリバリーゴッド夜トでございます
Yato.
夜ト
お　日和か
Oh, Hiyori!
What's up?
何々　どうした
Um, would you like to visit the Yushima Tenjin shrine tonight for the first shrine visit of the new year?
あのう　今日の夜
湯島天神に初詣に来ませんか
Huh?!
つうかなんてわざわざ髭爺んとこに詣でなきゃいけねぇんだ
Why do you have to visit that geezer?
You should visit me!
俺に詣でろ
Well, I have some big exams coming up...
だって受験生ですし
つうかお前社ねぇじゃん
Plus, you don't even have a shrine.
雪音のバイト代で今すぐ買えば
I'm using your part-time
wages to buy one, then!
What are you, a tax collecting god?!
この引きも神が
There's going to be a ton of food stalls and stuff there, you know.
お参りしなくても　屋台がたくさん出るよ
屋台
Food stalls?!
行く
We'll be there!
I want some candied fruit!
俺　杏子飴食う
では　後ほど
See you soon, then!
Let's go all out with this shrine visit!!
Yama
本気で…か
All out, huh?
走ったりしないのよ
Now don't run, okay?
着崩れたら大変ですからね
You don't want this to get too loose.
はい
Okay.
こっち向いて
Turn this way.
似合ってるわよ
You look lovely!
行ってきます
Well, I'm off.
So that's the half-Phantom
that misleads Yato?
あれが夜トを惑わす半妖か
Yes.
ええ
Let's slay her, Reiki.
斬るぞ　零器
Wait.
待って
どうした
What is it?
あの子はまだ使い道があるのよ
We still may have use for her.
Noragami
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
ra
ga
mi
ra
ga
mi
ra
ga
mi
Hiyori!
ひより
mi
ga
ra
No
Abby New Year...
あけましておめでとう
What happened to going all out?!
なん　本気は
We still are! I'm offering
a ton of money this year!
本気本気
今年はお賽銭弾むの
受験ついでに高校デビューすっかな
Besides the tests, we're gonna be entering high school!
きたれ　モテ期
Grant me popularity!
はしゃぐな　馬鹿
Simmer down, dummy.
Seriously, it's pretty much a given that our
whole class will move on to high school.
高校っても　うちらはクラスごと繰りあげるんだってぱ
ひよりよりは浮かれてないし
I'm not as thrilled as Hiyori is, at least.
I am not thrilled!
浮かれてないよ
S-Say, someone might join us later.
あ　あのね
もしかしたら　後で人数増えるかもしれないんだけど
I hope you don't mind.
いいかな
お　男か
A m-man?! Is that why you're all dressed up?!
それで振袖か
So you want to win his heart by saying, "I'm a different person this year"!
去年とは違う私を見せてときめかそうって魂胆か
N-No! It's not like that!
ち　違う
そういうんじゃなくて
Staking it all on New Year's? You've got guts!
新年一発目に勝負かけるんだ なかなかやるな
だから　そういうんじゃないって
Seriously, it's not like that!
Come on! Quit it!
もう　やめてよ
Popularity! Popularity!
Popularity! Gimme popularity!
モテ期　モテ期　モテ期　モテ期
もしくはモテ期　ダメならモテ期
無事高校生になれますように
Please let me move to high school without any trouble.
もしよければ
いままでなんとなくお参りしてたけど
Until now, I used to visit
shrines just because, but...
Please let me continue to
have fun with all my friends.
これからも皆と一緒に楽しく居られますように
I want some octopus dumplings!
たこ焼き食べたいな
うまそう
Looks yummy!
Hey, Hiyori. You gonna buy some, too?
ねぇひより　あんたも買う
Oh, yeah.
Yato! Wait!
夜ト　待て
Hiyori! Hey, Hiyori!
ひより
おい　ひより
Hiyori!
ひより
Her first snooze attack of the year.
新春初爆睡芸来た
Aw, man.
We missed ringing in the new year all
because you had to take your sweet time!
夜トがもたもたしてるせいで 年が明けちゃったじゃんかぁ
It's not my fault!
しょうがねえだろ
俺はカビ汚れを見逃せない性分なの
Every last bit of moldy grime I see is just begging to be cleaned up!
I hope Hiyori hasn't gotten
sick of waiting for us.
ひより　待ちくたびれてっかな
A text message?
メール
Another regular Phantom-slaying job.
またいつものあやかし退治か
Wait, it says that it should
be right here, actually.
って このあたりじゃねえか
あやかしが出るっての
Come, Sekki!
来い　雪器
豊葦原の中津国
Thou who dares desecrate
this land of the rising sun!
荒び足らせぬ「彼」のものよ
With my advent, I, the Yato god...
我 夜ト神来たり降り
lay waste with Sekki...
雪器を以って砕きふせ
and expel thy vast defilement!
種々の障り穢れを打ち払わん
Rend!
斬
Nicely done!
いい仕上がり
Thanks.
どうも
Huh?! How many are there?!
まだ　こんなにいんのかよ
Calm down, Yukine! It'll be okay!
落ち着け　雪音
大丈夫だ
You've changed, Yukine.
雪音　お前は変わった
いや　これからもっと変われる
And you're going to change even more!
Believe in yourself!
今の自分を信じろ
Now show me, god named Yato,
見せてもらうぞ　夜ト神
the power of the Regalia
you have tempered.
お前の鍛えた　その神器の力
夜ト
Yato?
Where did you go?
どこ
I don't smell him.
夜トの匂いがしない
Nora...
野良
H-Hello.
こん　こんばんは
Say, have you seen Yato?
ねぇ　夜ト知らない
I thought he came this way, but...
こっちに来たと思ったんだけど
Huh? Is that—
あれ　それ
あやかしの分際で　気安く話しかけないでくれる
Could you not speak so casually to me, you lowly Phantom?
Huh?
When did I...
いつの間に
You played a big part in his ablution.
あなた　禊では大活躍だったわね
You were watching?
見てたの
That was such the perfect time to revoke his name, too.
せっかくあの子の名を取るいい機会だったのに
Huh?!
Wait—
ちょっ
You're quite fast on your feet, I see.
逃げ足が速いのね
Go for her Cord.
「緒」を狙いなさい
But try not to accidentally bite it off.
うっかり噛みちぎらないようにね
Why are you attacking me?!
どうして私を
Why?
どうして
Because I don't like you.
気に入らないからよ
こいつら　キリがないんだけど
These things just keep coming!
Yeah, they really are persistent!
ああ本当 しつこいな
They disappeared.
消えた
What a shame.
残念
I guess that's all my Masked Ones can do.
面付きじゃここまでか
Were you scared?
怖かった
Even scarier things will
happen now, you know.
もっと怖いことがこれから起こるわ
Huh?
A god of calamity known
as Rabou has woken.
蠃蚌というまがつがみが目を覚ましたの
Rabou...
蠃蚌
"Rabou-sama, Rabou-sama! I beg of you!"
蠃蚌様　蠃蚌様　どうかお願いします
You mean...
それって
If someone wishes for it, Rabou can easily kill a Phantom...
蠃蚌は人の願いがあれば 簡単に切ってしまうのよ
or a person...
あやかしも　人も
or a god.
神様も
Rabou, a blood-soaked, aberrant god of calamity from the Far Shore...
血を浴び　彼岸に狂いざくまがつがみ
has come to kill Yato.
蠃蚌が夜トを殺しに来る
Huh?!
But... But Yato has
Yukine-kun with him.
で　でも
夜トには雪音くんがついてるし
あなたと会って　夜トは弱くなった
Yato has grown weak
after meeting you.
So, please...
だからお願い
Just stop existing.
あなたは　いなくなって
Over here! Come get me!
ほらほら　こっちだ
Looks like you've rounded them all up!
これでほとんど集まった感じ
よし
All right.
Show off the power of your callused heart!
触るもの皆傷つけて
昼の校舎窓ガラス
The heart that demolished the school windows... and hurt everything it touched!
壊して回ったギザギザハートの底力
見せちゃって
やめろ
Stop!
Let's take all of them out, Yukine!
一気に片付けるぞ　雪音
豊葦原の中津国
Thou who dares desecrate
this land of the rising sun!
荒び足らせぬ「彼」のものよ
我夜ト神来たり降り
With my advent, I, the Yato god...
lay waste with Sekki...
雪器を以って砕きふせ
and expel thy vast defilement!
種々の障り穢れを打ち払わん
Rend!
斬
That's all of them, Yukine.
これで全部だな
雪音
Now let's hurry to Hiyori!
ひよりんとこ急ぐぞ
Yeah!
Candied fruit! Candied fruit!
杏子飴　杏子飴
Ten candied fruits using Hiyori's money!
ひよりの金で杏子飴
十本
奢らせすぎたろ
That's too much, you freeloader!
That's...
あれが
That's how strong Yato is now?
あれが夜ト神の　今の力
Now don't pass out on your way home!
帰り道で爆睡すんじゃねえぞ
I'll be careful.
気をつける
Hiyori!
ひより
あけましておめでとう　ひより
Happy New Year, Hiyori!
ことよろ
HNY!
なになに　もう帰っちゃうの
Whoa, what? You're going home already?
まだ屋台出てたぞ
The food stalls are still open! Let's go!
行こう行こう
初お供え物　行っちゃおう
It can be your first food offering of the year!
Oh, maybe your first money offering of the year could come before that?
その前に　俺に初お賽銭くれちゃう系
あれ
Huh?
あのう
Um...
What is it, Hiyori?
どうした　ひより
Who are you?
どなたですか　あなた
Whatever happens I will surely call out your name
ki
mi
no
na
ma
e
na
ni
ga
a
tte
mo
ka
na
ra
zu
yo
bu
ka
ra
君の名前 何があっても
必ず呼ぶから
Your heart is all jagged
ki
mi
wa
gi
za
ha
a
to
no
mo
chi
nu
shi
君はぎざぎざハートの持ち主
So you hurt anything you touch
fu
re
ru
mo
no
wa
na
n
de
mo
ki
zu
tsu
ke
ru
触れるものは何でも傷つけ
Those eyes that frown at everything
se
ka
i
no
su
be
te
wo
ni
ra
mi
tsu
ke
te
世界のすべてを睨み付けて
その目は言うんだ
They are saying "I'm here! See me!"
so
no
me
wa
i
un
da
bo
ku
wa
ko
ni
iru
「僕はここにいる」
誰かが笑ってた
Someone was laughing at you
da
re
ka
ga
wa
ra
tte
ta
だから引いたんだ その境界線
So you put that barrier around you
da
ka
ra
hi
i
tan
da
so
no
kyo
u
ka
i
sen
それなら
But I'll reach in there with my hand
so
re
na
ra
wa
ta
shi
ga
so
no
te
wo
hi
ku
私はその手を引く
さぁ
And bring you out
tsu
re
te
ku
ka
ra
連れてくから
言えないなら
If you don't have words, just grasp my hand
i
e
na
i
ra
ko
no
te
wo
tsu
yo
ku
ni
gi
tte
この手を強く握って
And don't let go
ha
na
sa
i
de
離さないで
君はもう一人じゃないんだって
I want you to know that you
ki
mi
wa
mo
u
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
n
da
tte
知ってほしいんだよ
Are not alone any more
shi
tte
ho
shi
in
da
yo
What's wrong, Veena?
Have you caught a cold—
どうしたビーナ
風邪でもひいた
It looks like you're sneezing, too, Kazuma.
そういうお前もくしゃみが出ているじゃないか　カズマ
On the next Noragami: "Abandoned God."
次回　ノラガミ
捨てられた神
Huh? These hairballs...
この毛玉は
Oh, Kuraha must be shedding.
Abandoned God
Next Episode
クラハの換毛期か